Jaclene Sini

Front-End Developer

770-880-0312 | Brooklyn, New York | They/Them jaclenesini@gmail.com | in/jac-lene | github.com/jac-lene

SUMMARY

People-focused frontend software engineer with a desire to produce compassionate, engaging, and empowering products. With past careers in a wide variety of industries, I have a confident and creative approach to work, life, and communication. Working with code and software engineering has allowed me to apply this specialized background to create high-quality programming and thoughtful product engagement.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages - JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL Databases - Postgres SQL, MongoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api, Node.js Libraries and Frameworks - React (hook-based), Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap Other Software - Git, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Figma

PROJECTS

SockLab Customizer, Frontend / Backend | Full Stack Developer

July 2022

- SockLab is a design experience that allows the user to customize a sock knitting pattern using a visual laboratory inspired by the custom design experience of shoe brands like Nike and Vans.
- Designed and engineered over a fast-paced 3 week period, SockLab is a full stack MERN website with full CRUD functionality and RESTful Django framework.
- Engineered with React and Django, Postgres SQL, Javascript, HTML, SVG components and CSS styling.

Align Astrological Dating, Frontend / Backend | Full Stack Developer, Project Manager

May 2022

- Align is a swipe-based dating website that utilizes the zodiac to determine match compatibility.
- Designed and engineered over 2 week period, Align is a full CRUD MERN website with RESTful routing.
- Engineered with React, MongoDB and 3rd party APIs as well as Javascript, HTML, and CSS styling.
- Programmed with a team of 3 engineers to complete autonomous components over a 2 week sprint, collectively
 debugging code, delivering materials with tight timelines and ensuring effective component collaboration.

GYST Habit Tracker, Github | Full Stack Developer

April 2022

- Gyst presents your daily doings in a minimalist, gender neutral interface with an at-a-glance view of your habits.
- Full CRUD, RESTful mobile application utilizing MongoDB and user generated data.
- Engineered with EJS, HTML, CSS, Javascript and Mongoose.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer

New York, New York

i will if u will - Social Organizing Startup

September 2022 - Present

- Lead engineer developing best practices, software architecture, workflow and project management.
- Collaborates closely with other founding members to synthesize outside stakeholder expectations into a thoughtful UI and effective product development.
- Leading product concept and development for a scalable, global social organizing platform for web and mobile.

Tech Editor and Grader Brooklyn Tweed · Freelance

Remote

Mar 2017 - Oct 2019

- Re-engineered deliverables using mathematical calculations, style standards and pattern drafting knowledge to incorporate size inclusivity, diversity, and style standards across product lines.
- Created and implemented system standards and style sheets for uniform language across departments.
- Quality assured product for mathematical accuracy, readability, and brand compliance.

Props Production Assistant Netflix, NBC/Universal

New York, New York Jun 2018 - Nov 2018

- Managed 100-200 high value products and quality assured prop selection for cross department collaborators.
- Fabricated props, conducted research, and organized purchases from over 100 outside stakeholders.
- Interfaced with high level, Oscar winning celebrity clientele to discuss and finalize cross department decisions.

Yarn Coordinator Vogue Knitting Magazine/Soho Publishing

New York, New York June 2016 - May 2018

- Project managed a team of over 200 designers, facilitating the production of 150 250 deliverables per 3 month magazine and book cycle.
- Rehabilitated and refreshed social media campaigns by curating specialized content, increasing engagement by 75% within the first 2 months.
- Improved live event sales by targeting a wider age range and a more diverse demographic, resulting in sales growth for 300-500 stakeholders and affiliates.
- Designed and fabricated knitwear featured on The Late Show with Stephen Colbert and showcased by actress Krysten Ritter, enhancing company visibility by engaging over 3.81M viewers.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Remote

Software Engineering Immersive

January 2022 - July 2022

 Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

Savannah College of Art and Design Film and Television, BFA

Savannah, Georgia September 2008 - May 2012